

MEHREEN MUMTAZ

Teacher & Graphic Designer

About Me

Creative and skilled diverse Fashion Designer and Artist with a blend of mass communication knowledge. I have 2 years experience of teaching in a reputed school and also having in-depth knowledge of diverse clothing mediums and techniques, gained while working as a designer for 5 years along with running my self-owned online apparel business since 2015. I am reliable, flexible and hardworking who can work well under pressure, either as an individual or a part of a team and a multitasker, the same shall help me go up the specialist ladder.

Personal Details

Date of Birth 11-09-1989

Nationality Pakistani

Religion Muslim

Marital Status Married

Experience

AMERICAN LYCETUFF DNK SCHOOL SYSTEM BAHRIA ENCLAVE, ISLAMABAD March 2023-August 2023 ART TEACHER (Grade 1-5) SUBJECT TEACHER (Grade 1-7) HOMEROOM TEACHER (Grade 3)

Responsibilities:

- Provide an exciting and welcoming classroom experience to students during homeroom time for a great and refreshing start of the day.
- Taking attendance
- Maintaining student's records.
- Ensure the student's growth and achievement.
- · Lesson Planning.
- Taking Art lessons

UNITY INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL BANI GALA, ISLAMABAD March 2018-2020 ART TEACHER (Primary Section)

Responsibilities:

- · Teach students painting, drawing and printmaking.
- Provide an exciting classroom experience to students during art sessions.
- Assess, evaluate, and grade student's performance in arts subject.
- Plan and present art displays and exhibitions designed to exhibit student's work for the school.

BASICS (Karachi Based Emerging Brand) 2016-2021

FREELANCE DRESS DESIGNER

Working as a freelance dress designer I was responsible to design their pret collection following latest trends.

OWNER, Shopping Craze (Online Apparel and Accessories business) Islamabad, Pakistan 2015-present

FIVERR October 2020-present FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Working as a freelance graphic designer on Fiverr.com. I am mainly working on picture editing and designing logos, flyers, and social media posts using Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator and Canva.

Email & Contact no.

Email

meheen.mumtaz@yahoo.c

Contact 0332-5328876 0323-5084000

Social Links

Instagram @mehreen_mumtazz

References

Asim Bilal T: 03009543329

E: asim.bilal@gmail.com

NAWA-E-WAQT NEWSPAPER (Islamabad) September 2023 - December 2023 INTERNEE

Ad group Advertising (Islamabad) July 2010- September 2010 INTERNEE

INP NEWS AGENCY (Islamabad) July 2016- August 2016 INTERNEE

Education

DRAWING/PAINTING CERTIFICATION National College of Arts

February 2024-Present

DIGITAL MARKETING & DATA ANALYTICS & BUSSINESS INTELLIGENCE CERTIFICATION Digiskills

July 2024-present

Freelancing & Graphic Design CERTIFICATION Digiskills 2019

MASTERS IN MASS COMMUNICATION Allama Iqbal Open University, Islamabad, Pakistan — 2014-2016

BACHELORS IN TEXTILE AND FASHION DESIGNING National Textile Institute NTI, Islamabad, Pakistan (Affiliation with Sarhad University KPK) — 2009-2011

DIPLOMA IN DRESS MAKING AND DRESS
DESIGNING
Poly-technic Institute of Technical Education for
Women , Islamabad, Pakistan — 2005-2008

Portfolio



Potrait (Oil Paint)



Calligraphy Wall
Mural



Textile Design